{"tossups": [{"question": "In the Athenian Bouphonia festival, an ax that had been used to slay an ox was subjected to one of these events and thrown into the sea. The first one of these events occurred after Halirrhothius was killed for assaulting Alcippe. During one of these events, Apollo gave a speech about the supremacy of paternal rights, because men \"plant the seed\"; that one of these events was decided by Athena, setting a tradition for Athenian events of this type. Ares was the subject of the first of these events, which, like a later event of this sort experienced by Orestes, occurred on the Areopagus hill. For 10 points, Aeacus (EE-uh-cuss), Rhadamanthus, and Minos's role in Hades is to judge what sorts of legal proceedings?", "answer": "trials [or judgements until \"judge\" is read; or obvious equivalents; prompt on legal proceedings until read]", "category": "Mythology", "subcategory": "Mythology", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>trials</u></b> [or <b><u>judgements until \"judge\" is read</u></b>; or <b><u>obvious equivalents</u></b>; prompt on <u>legal proceedings until read</u>]", "acceptable": ["trials", "judgements until \"judge\" is read", "obvious equivalents"], "promptable": ["legal proceedings until read"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "With his wife, Alicia Patterson, a member of this family founded the newspaper Newsday. This was the alphabetically first of the two families that partnered to build the Million Dollar Bridge to transport copper from the town of Kennicott. Fifteen employees of a company owned by this family were killed by Pancho Villa's men in an attack on a train near Santa Isabel. A member of this family supported Richard Ballinger in the Cunningham claims dispute, and, along with J. P. Morgan, formed the Alaska Syndicate. Its patriarch, Meyer, acquired the American Smelting and Refining Company. A member of this family named Solomon befriended Hilla von Rebay, leading to an interest in contemporary art. For 10 points, name this family that commissioned Frank Lloyd Wright to design a New York City museum", "answer": "Guggenheim family ", "subcategory": "American History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Guggenheim family</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Guggenheim family"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This artist restaged many of George Dureau's images of dwarfs and amputees. In an expensive photograph by this artist, four silk panels surround a platinum print on linen, depicting Andy Warhol. In a departure from his usual subject matter, this photographer shot many close-ups of calla lilies. This photographer's Black Book has been criticized for its exploitative fetishization of black men. Restrictions on National Endowment of the Arts grants were enacted after it had funded a retrospective for this photographer at the Corcoran Gallery, called The Perfect Moment, soon after his 1989 death of complications from AIDS. For 10 points, name this American artist who took extremely sadomasochistic and homoerotic photographs.", "answer": "Robert Mapplethorpe", "subcategory": "Other Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "Robert <b><u>Mapplethorpe</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Robert Mapplethorpe"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In a novel by this author, a character's claim that her entire family is dead is shown to be a lie when her entire family arrives from Madrid, Texas. A character created by this author rants at her stepmother after finding her mother's old breadboard has been ruined. In a story by this author, the narrator is woken up at 6:30 a.m. when her uncle throws firecrackers in her room. A novel by this author centers on the death and funeral of a Mount Salus judge, who dies while recovering from an eye surgery in New Orleans. A story by this author is set on the Fourth of July after Stella-Rondo returns home with the two-year-old Shirley-T. For 10 points, name this Mississippian author of The Optimist's Daughter and \"Why I Live at the P.O.\".", "answer": "Eudora Welty ", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Eudora <b><u>Welty</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Eudora Welty"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Using the air mass, or AM, one-point-five model, the theoretical efficiency of these devices is capped at around 33.7 percent. A groundbreaking one of these devices consisted of a TCO layer of aluminum- doped zinc oxide over the quaternary compound CIGS, and was fabricated via the superstrate configuration. Their tandem form features semiconductors with different bandgaps, greatly increasing efficiency. Though not related to imaging, the efficiency of these devices is in direct proportion to their fill factor. The fastest payback for these devices comes from their thin-film cadmium telluride variety. The most common example of these devices is a simple silicon p\u00c2\u2013n junction in which electrons are excited by incident photons. For 10 points, identify these devices that convert sunlight into electricity.", "answer": "solar cells [or photovoltaic cell; or PV cell; do not accept \"photocells\" or \"photoelectric cells\" or \"PE cells\"] ", "subcategory": "Chemistry", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>solar cells</u></b> [or <b><u>photovoltaic cell</u></b>; or <b><u>PV cell</u></b>; do not accept \"photocells\" or \"photoelectric cells\" or \"PE cells\"]", "acceptable": ["solar cells", "photovoltaic cell", "PV cell"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This writer wrote about a man and \"his last gruel of winter seeds caked in his stomach\" in a poem concluding, \"In the old man-killing parishes I will feel lost, unhappy and at home\". Another of his poems describes how \"bubbles gargled delicately, bluebottles wove a strong gauze (goz) of sound around the smell\". In addition to writing about wanting to go to Aarhus (AR-hooss) to see the \"peat- brown head\" of \"The Tollund Man\", this poet wrote about a \"rat-grey fungus\" that leads the speaker to conclude, \"It wasn't fair that all the lovely canfuls smelt of rot\". This poet of \"Blackberry-Picking\" wrote about the death of his younger brother in a poem ending, \"A four foot box, a foot for every year\". For 10 points, name this Irish poet who included \"Mid-Term Break\" in Death of a Naturalist and translated Beowulf.", "answer": "Seamus Heaney (SHAY-mus HEE-nee) [or Seamus Justin Heaney] ", "subcategory": "British Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Seamus <b><u>Heaney</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Seamus Heaney"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "SHAY-mus HEE-nee"}, {"question": "A. P. Flitney and Derek Abbott discussed the quantum variation of this problem, discovering that if Alice has access to quantum strategies, then probabilities do not change, but if the particles are maximally entangled, a classical strategy is still the best strategy for Bob. The same logic used to resolve this conundrum can also be used to resolve the paradox proposed by Joseph Bertrand, which involves three gold coins and three silver coins. This problem, which was recast by Martin Gardner using prisoner, execution, and freedom, centers on two goats. Conditional probability shows that \"one- half\" is the answer to this problem if another door is chosen after being asked by the namesake person to swap doors. For 10 points, name this probability problem named for the host of Let's Make a Deal.", "answer": "Monty Hall problem", "category": "Social Science", "subcategory": "Social Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Monty Hall problem</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Monty Hall problem"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The revealed letters of Kenneth de Courcy speak of a plot that would have undone the primary outcome of this event. The lawyer John Goddard represented one party in this event, though he cautioned against further legal action because of a possible \"citizens' intervention\". After this event, its main subject traveled to Austria and went on to become Governor of the Bahamas during World War II. Stanley Baldwin forced this event by declaring a morganatic arrangement unacceptable. George VI ascended to the throne after this event, which was caused by the current king's desire to marry the divorcee Wallis Simpson. For 10 points, name this event in which the reigning British monarch in 1936 renounced his claim to the throne.", "answer": "abdication of Edward VIII [prompt on the Abdication Crisis, accession of George VI, or descriptive answers, such as Edward VIII stepping down]", "subcategory": "European History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>abdication of Edward VIII</u></b> [prompt on the <u>Abdication Crisis, accession of George VI,</u> or <u>descriptive answers, such as Edward VIII stepping down</u>]", "acceptable": ["abdication of Edward VIII"], "promptable": ["Abdication Crisis, accession of George VI,", "descriptive answers, such as Edward VIII stepping down"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "After writing down the names of 77 officials of a town, this man punishes them \"with desert thorns and briers\". His son was the subject of a parable about a thornbush becoming the king of the other trees. He's not Greek, but this man's son was killed when a woman threw a millstone on his skull. This leader was told to dismiss any man who did not drink water by lapping it like a dog. Also known as \"Jerubbaal\", this person had a dictatorial son who ruled Shechem named Abimelech. After putting out a fleece and asking God to give him signs, this man destroyed an altar of Baal. With only a force of 300 men, this man used trumpets and torches to confuse and defeat a much larger Midianite force. For 10 points, what Old Testament judge names a group which hands out free Bibles?", "answer": "Gideon [or Jerubbaal until read]", "category": "Religion", "subcategory": "Religion", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Gideon</u></b> [or <b><u>Jerubbaal until read</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Gideon", "Jerubbaal until read"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "ABC News reporter Brian Ross was cited in District Court for illegally trying to interview this man in June 2016 while he was walking to an elevator. In the parking lot of a funeral home, this man was reportedly told by Jolene Burdge that \"your secret didn't die in there with my brother\". Fuels America terminated its contract with the lobbying firm Dickstein Shapiro after this man resigned from it in May 2016. That resignation occurred after he was indicted for unlawfully structuring large cash withdrawals as part of a scheme to pay a person known as \"Individual A\". That investigation led to 2016 revelations that this man had sexually molested boys while working as a high school wrestling coach. For 10 points, name this now disgraced former Speaker of the House from Illinois.", "answer": "Dennis \"Denny\" Hastert [or John Dennis Hastert]", "category": "Current Events", "subcategory": "Current Events", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Dennis \"Denny\" Hastert</u></b> [or <b><u>John Dennis Hastert</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Dennis \"Denny\" Hastert", "John Dennis Hastert"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Late in his career, this thinker collaborated with Charles Benight in various articles challenging the diathesis-stress model's application to depression and PTSD. This psychologist developed a type of therapy by working with people afraid of snakes and inviting them to drape a snake over their neck. In a 1997 book, this thinker described the title belief as what \"you believe you can do with what you have\". That book, Self-Efficacy, expanded this person's landmark text on social cognitive theory titled Social Foundations of Thought and Action. This originator of social learning theory observed how children imitated adult models who yelled things like \"Sock him!\" while attacking an inflatable object painted like a clown. For 10 points, what psychologist conducted the Bobo doll experiment?", "answer": "Albert Bandura", "category": "Social Science", "subcategory": "Social Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Albert Bandura</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Albert Bandura"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A guerrilla group in this nation, which was led by a man known as the \"Bronze Titan\", employed a tactic dubbed the \"machete charge\". Arsenio Marti\u0301nez Campos tried to contain an uprising in this nation by constructing a defensive trocha from Ju\u0301caro to Moro\u0301n. Calixto Garci\u0301a and Antonio Maceo were leaders of this nation's mambises (mom-BEE-says) who fought in a short-lived uprising here, the Little War. The Pact of Zanjo\u0301n ended a war in this nation that began when Carlos Manuel de Ce\u0301spedes issued the \"Cry of Yara\". This nation's peasants were forced into concentration camps by Valeriano \"Butcher\" Weyler. This country's independence movement fought the Ten Years' War against Spain. For 10 points, name this island nation where the USS Maine exploded in Havana Harbor.", "answer": "Republic of Cuba [or Republica de Cuba]", "subcategory": "World History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Republic of Cuba</u></b> [or <b><u>Republica de Cuba</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Republic of Cuba", "Republica de Cuba"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The first modern artwork of this type was created in a medium composed of wax, resins, gasoline, and oils, called the namesake \"color\" of a pseudonymous artist. A rotating stage in a \"Polyforum Cultural\" allows visitors to experience a large example of these artworks showing a man emerging from an amate tree. Dr. Atl taught an artist who depicted vultures wearing clerical collars and a skeleton giving birth in an artwork of this type. Four propeller-like shapes surround an orb held by a fist, inside of which a cell divides, in an artwork of this type that was destroyed because of its Lenin imagery. For 10 points, name these artworks made by David Siqueiros, Jose\u0301 Clemente Orozco, and Diego Rivera, that were directly painted on surfaces.", "answer": "Mexican murals [prompt on frescos, since many of these were painted using fresco]", "subcategory": "Visual Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Mexican murals</u></b> [prompt on <u>frescos,</u> since many of these were painted using fresco]", "acceptable": ["Mexican murals"], "promptable": ["frescos,"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Thermolysin conjugates four calcium ions and an ion of this element. TIMPs inhibit proteins that coordinate this element called matrix metallo-proteinases. The Really Interesting New Gene domain binds to two ions of this element. As in TALENs, Fok-one restriction enzymes are fused with proteins binding to this element to perform genome editing. This element coordinates with three imidazole (ih- mih-DA-zohl) rings in the active site of carbonic anhydrase. A class of proteins binding this element includes fold groups called treble clef and gag knuckle. It is bound by cysteine and histidine (HISS-tuh- deen) residues in proteins that grab onto substrates like DNA in namesake \"finger\" domains. For 10 points, name this element with atomic symbol Zn.", "answer": "zinc [or Zn until it is read]", "subcategory": "Chemistry", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>zinc</u></b> [or <b><u>Zn until it is read</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["zinc", "Zn until it is read"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The speaker of this poem still sighs for a \"dark downward and vegetating kingdom\" that has been destroyed. This poem describes a man who is \"as lean as a compass needle\" and \"has an angry wrenlike vigilance, a greyhound's gentle tautness\". This poem describes some \"yellow dinosaur steamshovels\" that \"were grunting as they cropped up tons of mush and grass to gouge their underworld garage\". This poem, set in a \"Sahara of snow\" where an aquarium used to be, ends with the lines, \"a savage servility slides by on grease\". This poem's speaker recalls how William James \"could almost hear the bronze Negroes breathe\" at the dedication of the monument it describes. For 10 points, name this poem about the Robert Gould Shaw Memorial in Boston written by Robert Lowell.", "answer": "\"For the Union Dead\"", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>\"For the Union Dead\"</u></b>", "acceptable": ["\"For the Union Dead\""], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Followers of this man believed his right foot had the power to heal people's spleens. This king appointed Gauls to oversee the city of Aegae (EYE-guy) he captured after the Battle of the Aous River, but they angered the people by digging up ancient tombs. His son Ptolemy was slain during a failed attempt to put Cleonymus on the throne instead of Areus. This man died after a failed siege of Sparta in Argos after the mother of a soldier threw a tile that knocked him from his horse. When this man left Tarentum, he mused on the battlefield he was leaving for Carthage and its current uneasy ally. After winning the Battle of Asculum against the Romans, he commented, \"one more such victory and we are undone\". For 10 points, what Greek king of Epirus gives his name to victories in which the winner suffers devastating losses?", "answer": "Pyrrhus of Epirus", "subcategory": "History Classical", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Pyrrhus of Epirus</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Pyrrhus of Epirus"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "An editor of this publication wrote the editorial \"A Book for Burning?\", in which he argued that Rupert Sheldrake produced \"the literature of intellectual aberrations\". That editor of this publication also wrote the 1983 editorial \"No Need for Panic about AIDS\". It currently prints short stories called \"Futures\". Norman Lockyer created this publication in 1869 and named it for a line from a Wordsworth poem. Its article \"Coping with Peer Rejection\" admitted mistakes like rejecting the work of Robert Huber and Hartmut Michel. In 1997, this British publication printed a landmark article about Dolly the sheep, and in 1953, it published Watson and Crick's paper explaining the structure of DNA. For 10 points, what publication, along with Science, is the world's most cited scientific journal?", "answer": "Nature", "subcategory": "Other Science", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Nature</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Nature"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This composer included a minor-key episode marked \"Im Legendenton\" (LAY-gun-DENT-in), or \"in the style of a legend\", in the first movement of a three-movement piano fantasy in C major. He wrote a set of piano etudes in the form of a theme, nine variations, and a finale. Easy pieces such as \"Knecht Ruprecht\" and \"The Merry Farmer\" are found in his Album for the Young. This composer used an \"A E- flat C B\" motif in a piece where the fiery and docile sides of his personality are contrasted in back-to- back movements titled \"Florestan\" and \"Eusebius\". The dream of a young child is the subject of the \"Tra\u0308umerei\" (TROWM-rye) movement of his Kinderszenen (kin-dust-SANE-in). For 10 points, name this composer whose Carnaval includes a movement depicting his wife Clara.", "answer": "Robert Schumann", "subcategory": "Auditory Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Robert Schumann</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Robert Schumann"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This thinker used the example of a slave who must hold a chamberpot for his master to argue that what is unbearable differs from person to person. This thinker, who famously thought that one must behave in life as at a dinner party, argued that students ought to study the disciplines of desire, action, and assent as part of his \"doctrine of the three topics\". This thinker's assertion that \"some things are in our control and some are not\" formed that basis of his distinction between the prohairetic and the aprohairetic. Marcus Aurelius' Meditations frequently quotes this thinker whose sayings were collected by his student Arrian into the Enchiridion. For 10 points, name this late Stoic philosopher whose teachings are collected in his Discourses.", "answer": "Epictetus", "category": "Philosophy", "subcategory": "Philosophy", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Epictetus</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Epictetus"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "n this novel, an army corporal uses the term \"Structural Oblique Formations\" to refer to a piece of installation art he has created, which is actually just a series of pillboxes. The narrator of this novel is unsure whether to end it with his thirtieth birthday or with a scene in which he is arrested as he travels up an escalator. A character in this novel is about to choke to death on a pin when he is shot by some soldiers in a basement. This novel's protagonist finds the finger of the murdered Sister Dorothea in a field, a crime for which he is confined to an asylum. Its protagonist is able to shatter glass with the sound of his voice and refuses to grow up at the age of three. For 10 points, name this novel about Oskar Matzerath, who beats the title instrument, written by Gunter Grass.", "answer": "The Tin Drum [or Die Blechtrommel]", "subcategory": "European Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>The Tin Drum</u></b> [or <b><u>Die Blechtrommel</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["The Tin Drum", "Die Blechtrommel"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A character in this poem \"moves in darkness\" that is greater than that of the woods or that of the \"shade of trees\". This poem derides hunters by claiming that \"they would have the rabbit out of hiding to please the yelping dogs\". This poem's speaker emphatically declares, \"Stay where you are until our backs are turned!\" in describing a sort of \"outdoor game\" that only has one player on either side. This poem describes boulders as being sometimes shaped like loaves and sometimes shaped like balls. This poem's talkative speaker walks with a surly neighbor who twice recites his father's saying that \"Good fences make good neighbors\". For 10 points, name this poem about fixing a barrier by Robert Frost.", "answer": "\"Mending Wall\"", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>\"Mending Wall\"</u></b>", "acceptable": ["\"Mending Wall\""], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}], "bonuses": []}